<!-- ================================================================== -->
<!-- =                        OpenORB XML profile                     = -->
<!-- ================================================================== -->

<!--
<!DOCTYPE OpenORB
    PUBLIC "-//openorb.sf.net//OpenORB Config//EN"
    "http://openorb.sf.net/config/OpenORB.dtd">
-->

<OpenORB profile="default"
  xmlns="http://openorb.sf.net/config"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
>
  <description>
  This config file contains all the modules available to users of
  OpenORB.  Users may import modules from this file into their
  configuration and modify the properties.
  </description>

  <!-- ********************************************************** -->
  <!--                           default modules                  -->
  <!-- ********************************************************** -->

  <!-- ********************************* -->
  <!--       openorb.server module        -->
  <!-- ********************************* -->
  <module name="openorb.server">
    <description>
    Properties affecting the orb server side. This module has no
    initializer and does not have to be imported.
    </description>

    <property name="enable" value="true">
      <description>
      Enable the ORB server side. The server side may be disabled for
      a client only orb.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="alias" value="">
      <description>
      The server alias. This is used in persistent references.  All
      servers listening on the same port, on the same host, with the
      same server alias can accept requests to persistent targets
      created previous incarnations of the same server.<p/>

      The command line alias -ORBSrvName=name can be used rather than
      -ORBopenorb.server.name=name, regardless of if this module is
      imported.
      </description>
    </property>
    <propalias name="alias" alias="SrvName" />

    <property name="maxQueueSize" value="0x7FFFFFFF" >
      <description>
      Maximum number of incomming requests to queue before replying
      with TRANSIENT exceptions.
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="maxManagerHeldRequests" value="0x7FFFFFFF" >
      <description>
      Maximum number of requests that an adapter with a manager in the
      HOLDING state can hold before incomming requests are replied to
      with TRANSIENT exceptions
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="minThreadPoolSize" value="2">
      <description>
       Minimum number of active threads in the request thread pool.
       The thread pool will never shrink beyond this size.
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="maxThreadPoolSize" value="10">
      <description>
      Maximum number of pool threads. The thread pool will never grow
      beyond this size.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="reapCloseDelay" value="600000">
      <description>
      Reaper close time in ms. If a channel is unused for at least
      this time it will be closed to conserve resources.  The thread
      pool also has a chance to shrink each time this event occours.
      With a value of 0 no reaper thread will be installed and thus no
      channels will be closed automatically.
      </description>
    </property>

    <!-- properties not usualy modified by users -->
    <property name="serverManagerClass" value="org.openorb.orb.net.ServerManagerImpl">
      <description>
      Server manager class. There is no alternative at present.
      </description>
    </property>

  </module>


  <!-- ************************* -->
  <!--   openorb.client module   -->
  <!-- ************************* -->

  <module name="openorb.client">
    <description>
    Properties affecting the orb client side. This module has no
    initializer and does not have to be imported.
    </description>

    <property name="reapPauseDelay" value="120000">
      <description>
      Reaper pause time in ms. If a channel is unused for at least
      this time it will be closed to conserve resources.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="enable" value="true">
      <description>
      Enable the client side. Server only orbs are possible however
      certain POA functionality will be unavailable.
      </description>
    </property>

    <!-- properties not usualy modified by users -->
    <property name="clientManagerClass" value="org.openorb.orb.net.ClientManagerImpl">
      <description>
      Client manager class. There is no alternative at present.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="bindings.discard_old" value="no">
      <description>
      NOTE: Proprietary Extension (Encorus, Twister Application Server)
      When this property is set to true the binding array will be completely discarded
      upon the reception of a LOCATION_FORWARD reply.
      The spec. requires that new endpoints will be added to the array but the
      old ones should not be removed completely as they might become valid
      again.
      This feature is currently used to achieve some kind of load balancing (LBS)
      for EJB objects for the EJB container of a J2EE application server.
      An IOR for application objects contains a set of endpoints: (AppObj, LBS).
      When a request to the application object fails the ORB transparently
      tries to switch to the second endpoint 'LBS'. The LBS is a service
      that notices when an application object request arrives that the
      connection to the application object must have died and reacts to such a
      request by creating a new object. After the creation of a new application
      object has been completed successfully a new IOR is created with the
      following set of endpoints: (NewAppObj, LBS). The new IOR is returned to
      the client via a LOCATION_FORWARD reply. With the discard_old property set
      to true the client ORB discards all old binding information by substituting
      it with the new bindings created from the endpoints of the just received IOR.
      This guarantees that new requests will not be sent to the old object endpoint
      anymore as this object has most probably died.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="policy_cache.enable" value="false">
      <description>
      The determination of the effective set of policies for an object is
      a very costly operation. In some environments it makes no sense of
      adjusting settings on the CORBA level like for EJB applications
      in a pure J2EE environment. The ORB wide policies will be applicable
      for all objects associated with this ORB. Therefore it should be
      possible to deactivate the costly merging of policies at the different
      levels: ORB, Thread, Object. This can be done by setting this property
      to true. No changing of policies will be possible after accessing the
      first object because the policies are already cached then.
      </description>
    </property>

  </module>


  <!-- ************************* -->
  <!--   openorb.pi module       -->
  <!-- ************************* -->

  <module name="openorb.pi">
    <description>
    Properties affecting the portable interceptors. There are
    currently no alternatives to the defaults for these
    properties. This module has no initializer and does not have to be
    imported.
    </description>

    <!-- properties not usualy modified by users -->

    <property name="ORBInitInfoClass" value="org.openorb.orb.pi.OpenORBInitInfo" />
    <property name="ServerManagerClass" value="org.openorb.orb.pi.SimpleServerManager" />
    <property name="ClientManagerClass" value="org.openorb.orb.pi.SimpleClientManager" />
    <property name="IORManagerClass" value="org.openorb.orb.pi.SimpleIORManager" />
  </module>


  <!-- *********************** -->
  <!--     openorb module      -->
  <!-- *********************** -->

  <module name="openorb">
    <description>
    Misc other properties. This module has no initializer and does not
    have to be imported.
    </description>

    <property name="dynany.enable" value="true">
      <description>
      Enable the use of the DynamicAnyFactory.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="kernel.ORBConnectorClass" value="org.openorb.orb.config.OpenORBConnector">
      <description>
      Define the orb connector class. There is currently no
      alternative.
      </description>
    </property>


    <property name="defaultInitRef" value="">
      <description>
      The default initial reference. This is used by
      resolve_initial_references when no other specific reference is
      available. The default behaviour is to have no default
      reference.<p/>

      The command line alias -ORBDefaultInitRef=str can be used rather
      than -ORBopenorb.defaultInitRef=str, regardless of if this
      module is imported.
      </description>
    </property>
    <propalias name="defaultInitRef" alias="DefaultInitRef" />


    <!-- debuging properties -->
    <property name="debug.trace" value="0">
      <description>
      Set the orb trace level<p/>

      The trace level specifies the trace level of the logger.
      The values 0-4 correspond to the following levels:
      FATAL|ERROR|WARN|INFO|DEBUG
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="debug.level" value="0">
      <description>
      Set the orb debug level<p/>

      The Jakarta LogKit provides only one debug level. To
      allow different debug levels we introduced the following
      debug level: OFF|LOW|MEDIUM|HIGH (0-3)
      </description>
    </property>


    <property name="useStaticThreadGroup" value="false">
      <description>
      Use static ThreadGroups for the orb threads. Can be useful to
      set to true when debugging the use of multiple orbs used in one
      app as it avoids large numbers of thread groups being created.
      </description>
    </property>
  </module>

  <!-- ************************** -->
  <!--      InitRef module        -->
  <!-- ************************** -->

  <module name="InitRef">
    <description>
    Module containing default initial references.  To add more initial
    services import and define properties with unique identifiers.
    Example import:<p/>

    <![CDATA[<import xlink:href="${openorb.home}config/default.xml#InitRef">]]>
    <![CDATA[  <property name="NameService" value="corbaloc::1.2@localhost/NameService" />]]>
    <![CDATA[</import>]]><p/>

    Also see the defaultInitRef property, defined in the openorb
    module.
    </description>

    <propertyset/>
  </module>


  <!-- ********************** -->
  <!--    compiler module     -->
  <!-- ********************** -->

  <module name="compiler" >
    <propertyset prefix="idl" >
      <description>
      The compiler module defines a single property set which allows
      additional include directories for the openorb compiler.  Each
      extra idl include directory property starts with idl and must
      have a unique extension. Example of import statement, adding an
      include: <p/>

      <![CDATA[<import xlink:href="${openorb.home}config/default.xml#compiler">]]>
      <![CDATA[  <property name="idl.xxx" value="URL" />]]>
      <![CDATA[</import>]]>
      <p/>

      The include dir "${openorb.home}idl" is always present in the
      compiler include path, it always appears last in the include
      list.
      </description>
    </propertyset>
  </module>


  <!-- *********************** -->
  <!--    BOA module           -->
  <!-- *********************** -->

  <module name="BOA" initializer="org.openorb.orb.adapter.boa.BOAInitializer" >
    <description>
    The BOA module. Import this module to use the BOA.
    </description>
  </module>


  <!-- ************************ -->
  <!--   POA module             -->
  <!-- ************************ -->

  <module name="POA" initializer="org.openorb.orb.adapter.poa.POAInitializer">
    <description>
    The POA module. Import this module to use the POA.
    </description>
  </module>


  <!-- ************************ -->
  <!--   Messaging module       -->
  <!-- ************************ -->

  <module name="Messaging" initializer="org.openorb.orb.messaging.MessagingInitializer">
    <description>
    The Messaging module. Import this module to use CORBA Messaging features.
    </description>
  </module>

  <!-- ************************* -->
  <!--   Forward Adapter module  -->
  <!-- ************************* -->

  <module name="CorbalocService" initializer="org.openorb.orb.adapter.fwd.ForwardInitializer" >
    <description>
    The corbaloc adapter module. When loaded it is possible to
    resolve corbaloc style addresses if they are registered.
    </description>
  </module>

  <module name="ForwardAdapter" >
    <description>
    The ForwardAdapter module has been renamed CorbalocService.
    </description>

    <import module="CorbalocService" />
  </module>


  <!-- *********************************** -->
  <!--   Default Corbaloc service          -->
  <!-- *********************************** -->

  <profile name="DefaultCorbalocService">
    <description>
    This profile loads the CorbalocService module, and sets the port
    number in iiop to 683, the default port.
    </description>

    <import module="CorbalocService" />
    <import module="iiop" >
      <property name="port" value="683" />
    </import>
  </profile>

  <profile name="InitialReferencesService">
    <description>
    Initial references service has been renamed CorbalocService.
    </description>

    <import module="DefaultCorbalocService" />
  </profile>


  <!-- **************************** -->
  <!--      BasicRefs profile       -->
  <!-- **************************** -->

  <profile name="BasicRefs">
    <description>
    Basic initial references. Just set the default initial reference.
    </description>

    <import module="openorb" >
      <property name="defaultInitRef" value="corbaname:rir:#InitialReferences" />
    </import>
  </profile>


  <!-- *********************** -->
  <!--    RMI  module          -->
  <!-- *********************** -->

  <module name="rmi" initializer="org.openorb.orb.rmi.RMIInitializer">
    <description>
    The rmi module initializer installs interceptors for correct
    Java like exception handling.
    </description>

    <property name="defaultorbSingleton" value="false">
      <description>
      When the first ORB instance is created the rmi DefaultORB will be
      initialized with the ORB instance. This is useful to avoid creating
      two ORBs when RMI-IIOP is used.
      Default false.
      </description>
    </property>
  </module>


  <!-- *********************** -->
  <!--    iiop module          -->
  <!-- *********************** -->

  <module name="iiop" initializer="org.openorb.orb.iiop.IIOPProtocolInitializer">
    <description>
    The IIOP protocol is the basic interoperability protocol between
    all orbs. It should be included in all profiles.
    </description>

    <!-- Properties controlling TCP/IP socket settings for transports -->

    <property name="boostReceivePriority" value="false">
      <description>
      Boosts the priority of receive worker threads, to avoid the BAD MAGIC
      problem under NT4.0 : true or false.
      Default false.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="sendBufferSize" value="0">
      <description>
      Sets the SO_SNDBUF socket property.
      A value of 0 indicates that the system default should be used.
      Default 0.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="recieveBufferSize" value="0">
      <description>
      Sets the SO_RCVBUF socket property.
      A value of 0 indicates that the system default should be used.
      Note that values above 64K cannot be set.
      Default 0.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="bufferedInputStreamSize" value="2048">
      <description>
      Sets the size of a BufferedInputStream used to wrap a socket's InputStream.
      A value of 0 indicates that no buffer should be used.
      Default 0, however set to 2048 bytes to optimize header reading.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="bufferedOutputStreamSize" value="0">
      <description>
      Sets the size of a BufferedOutputStream used to wrap a socket's OutputStream.
      A value of 0 indicates that no buffer should be used.
      By using this type of buffer it is possible to reduce the number of
      problems encountered by writing to Microsoft peers.
      Default 0.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="keepAlive" value="false">
      <description>
      Setting of keep alive for sockets: true or false. Default false.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="noDelay" value="true">
      <description>
      Setting of no delay for sockets: true or false. Default true.
      Note that this property replaces clientNoDelay and serverNoDelay.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="clientPortMin" value="-1">
      <description>
      Port range for outgoing client sockets number greater than
      1023: Default -1 meaning ignored.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="clientPortMax" value="-1">
      <description>
      Port range for outgoing client sockets number greater than
      1024: Default -1 meaning ignored.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="serverBacklogQueueLength" value="50">
      <description>
      Sets the backlog queue length used when listening to server sockets.
      Default 50.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="serverMaxSocketAcceptTimeout" value="250">
      <description>
      Sets the maximum socket accept timeout.
      If a timeout greater than this value is used by the listen method then
      the value specified by serverOverrideSocketTimeout is used.
      Default 250.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="serverMinSocketAcceptTimeout" value="0">
      <description>
      Sets the minimum socket accept timeout.
      If a timeout less than or equal tothis value is used by the listen
      method then the value specified by serverOverrideSocketTimeout is used.
      Note that setting this value to -1 will cause the protocol runner to
      block forever on accept.
      This should be set to 0 if SSLIOP is used.
      Default 0.
      </description>
    </property>

    <property name="serverOverrideSocketTimeout" value="250">
      <description>
      Sets the override timeout to be used in place when a requested timeout
      is out of range.
      Default 250.
      </description>
    </property>

    <propertyset prefix="address-mapping">
      <description>
      Sets the network address mappings used by the orb. The name specifies
      the original address and the value specifies the mapping.

      Addresses are specified in the format: host[:port] where the port
      is optional.

      Examples:

      - Map "corba.foo.com:port" to "192.168.0.2:port":
        <property name="corba.foo.com" value="192.168.0.2" />

      - Map "corba.foo.com:60" to "corba.foo.com:6661":
        <property name="corba.foo.com:60" value="corba.foo.com:6661" />

      - Map "corba.foo.com:port" to "foo.bar.com:6661":
        <property name="corba.foo.com" value="foo.bar.com:6661" />
      </description>

    </propertyset>

    <!-- Properties controlling what endpoints are published in IORs. -->
    <property name="hostname" value="">
      <description>
      Hostname to publish in IORs. If empty string or unspecified the
      published hostname will be determined by the publishIP setting.
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="publishIP" value="auto">
      <description>
      Publish IP address in IORs instead of hostname. The default
      setting of 'auto' will publish the IP address if the hostname is
      not a fqdn (does not contain a . ).  If true the IP address is
      always used.  For all other values the hostname is used.  If the
      hostname property is set this overrides this setting.
      </description>
    </property>
    <propertyset prefix="alternateAddr">
      <description>
      This property set defines alternate IIOP endpoints which are
      published in IORs. These are generaly servers on different targets.
      Each defined alternative should have a unique prefix.
      E.g. two alternative endpoints can be specified like this:
        <property name="endpoint1" value="localhost:6661" />
        <property name="endpoint2" value="localhost:6662" />
      The same can be specified via properties like this:
        iiop.alternateAddr.endpoint1 localhost:6661
        iiop.alternateAddr.endpoint2 localhost:6662
      </description>
    </propertyset>

    <!-- properties controlling the incomming server side. -->
    <property name="listenAddress" value="0.0.0.0">
      <description>
      Address to listen on on multi-homed host. Defaults to 0.0.0.0,
      all local addresses.
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="port" value="0">
      <description>
      Port for the iiop transport to listen on. Defaults to 0, any
      available port.<p/>
      Command line alias Port is available.
      </description>
    </property>
    <propalias name="port" alias="Port" />

    <!-- properties controlling bidirectional iiop -->
    <property name="allowBidir" value="true">
      <description>
      Allow bidirectional IIOP. For BiDirectional IIOP to be available
      at all this property must be set to true. It is set to true by
      default, since activating BiDirectional IIOP requires setting
      server and client side policies.
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="biDirOnlyServer" value="false">
      <description>
      When both allowBiDir and biDirOnlyServer are true, the server side
      orb will not listen for incomming requests. All incomming requests
      must be recieved over a bidirectional channel.
      </description>
    </property>

    <!-- Properties not usualy modified by users -->
    <property name="CDRInputStreamClass" value="org.openorb.orb.iiop.CDRInputStream">
      <description>
      CDRInputStream class. This is modified by the RMIoverIIOP
      module.
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="CDROutputStreamClass" value="org.openorb.orb.iiop.CDROutputStream">
      <description>
      CDRInputStream class. This is modified by the RMIoverIIOP
      module.
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="TransportServerInitializerClass"
        value="org.openorb.orb.iiop.IIOPTransportServerInitializer">
      <description>
      Server transport. This is modified by security services.
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="TransportClientInitializerClass"
        value="org.openorb.orb.iiop.IIOPTransportClientInitializer">
      <description>
      Client transport. This is modified by security services.
      </description>
    </property>

    <!--
      NOTE: This feature has now been superseded by the stream decoration framework!

      The following properties are helpful for tracing IIOP communication on the socket layer.
      Tools as Ethereal are not suitable when it comes to threading issues, i.e. finding bugs
      in badly synchronized code where different threads write to the same socket.
      However the mechanism for plugging other stream classes into the SocketFactory class
      can be used in many different ways. The description above states the original intention.
      -->
    <!--
    <property name="SocketOutputStreamClass" value="">
      <description>
      The OutputStream class that is created when SocketFactory.getOutputStream()
      is called. Possible values are wrapper classes that derive from java.io.OutputStream
      and flush the data finally into the socket buffer so that the communication link
      remains operational. The purpose of this property is that the class
      org.openorb.orb.util.DebugSocketOutputStream can be plugged in and the socket io can be
      traced and analyzed.
      Possible value: org.openorb.orb.util.DebugSocketOutputStream
      </description>
    </property>
    <property name="SocketInputStreamClass" value="">
      <description>
      The InputStream class that is created when SocketFactory.getInputStream()
      is called. Possible values are wrapper classes that derive from java.io.InputStream
      and read the data from the socket so that the socket communication
      still remains working. The purpose of this property is that the class
      org.openorb.orb.util.DebugSocketInputStream can be plugged in and the socket io can be
      traced and analyzed.
      Possible value: org.openorb.orb.util.DebugSocketInputStream
      </description>
    </property>
    -->

    <property name="deserializationEngine" value="lazy:auto">
      <description>
      This property allows configuration of the deserialization engine to
      use for RMI-IIOP and Java Serializable unmarshaling.

      Possible values:

      -   'auto': use automatic detection of the VM vendor and create a
        VM dependent marshaling engine. For a list of supported VMs
        please see the JavaDoc of the DeserializationKernelFactory class.

      -   'native': use a native library and JNI. This works with any VM but
        requires native code plus special setup of the VM environment in your
        operating system. The native library can be found in the native CVS module,
        including precompiled binaries for some platforms.

      -   'none': no support for RMI-IIOP, even if your VM supports it. Use this
        option to make sure that your software does not use any ORB features that
        depend on the VM.

      A prefix of 'lazy:' avoids creation at ORB startup time and defers creation of the
      deserialization engine until it is first used.

      Using 'lazy:' is not recommended if you need to achieve fail-fast behaviour.
      Using the 'lazy:' prefix is recommended if you are not sending Serializables
      over the wire - your application will work even if your VM is not supported
      for 'auto' or the operating system is not set up correctly for 'native'.

      Default value for deserializationEngine is 'lazy:auto'.
      </description>
    </property>

    <propertyset prefix="stream-decoration">
      <description>
      Sets the socket stream decoration strategies.
      Property names are used to set the order of application.
      Classes must implement the org.openorb.orb.net.SocketStreamDecorationStrategy.Factory
      interface.
      If this set is empty then the set defaults to the entries stated below.
      </description>

      <!-- Handles boostReceivePriority functionality -->
      <property name="1" value="org.openorb.orb.net.PriorityBoostingSocketStreamDecorationStrategy$Factory" />

      <!-- Handles bufferedInputStreamSize and bufferedOutputStreamSize functionality -->
      <property name="2" value="org.openorb.orb.net.BufferingSocketStreamDecorationStrategy$Factory" />

      <!-- Handles SocketInputStreamClass and SocketOutputStreamClass functionality -->
      <property name="3" value="org.openorb.orb.net.LegacySocketStreamDecorationStrategy$Factory" />

    </propertyset>

  </module>



  <!-- ********************************************************** -->
  <!--                       Default profiles                     -->
  <!-- ********************************************************** -->

  <profile name="default" >
    <description>
    The default profile load the POA, iiop and some basic initial
    references.
    </description>

    <import module="POA" />
    <import module="iiop" />
    <import profile="BasicRefs" />
  </profile>

  <profile name="rmi" >
    <description>
    A profile to load the POA, iiop, rmi and some basic initial
    references.
    </description>

    <import module="POA" />
    <import module="iiop" />
    <import module="rmi" />
    <import profile="BasicRefs" />
  </profile>


  <profile name="boa-only" >
    <description>
    This profile uses the BOA instead of the POA.
    </description>

    <import module="BOA" />
    <import module="iiop" />
    <import module="BasicRefs" />
  </profile>

  <profile name="client-only">
    <description>
    This profile enables only the client side orb.
    </description>

    <import module="openorb.server">
      <property name="enable" value="false"/>
    </import>

    <import module="iiop" />
    <import module="BasicRefs" />
  </profile>

</OpenORB>